Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative Records MS264
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative Records
2016 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative
MS264
22.24 Megabytes 30 files.
30 Digital Object(s)
This collection contains the administrative records of the Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative, a volunteer group that aims to mitigate food waste on the Tufts campus and in the community. Materials include the group constitution, meeting minutes, data and infographics, and photographs.
Content Description
This collection contains administrative records including the group constitution, minutes, and logo; infographics and data about food collection; photographs; and related newspaper articles.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Meeting minutes are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative, accession number MS-2020-015.
Biographical / Historical
Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative (TFRC) was founded in the fall of 2016 as a partnership between Tufts Dining, the Cambridge non-profit Food For Free (FFF), a number of Tufts academic departments including Enviromental Studies and Tisch College, and Tufts students. Through daily volunteer shifts, TFRC's aims to mitigate the food waste on campus and in the community, as well as to combat food insecurity by providing meals to those in need. TFRC includes two programs: Family Meals in Dewick and Carmichael, and the Leonard Carmichael Society (LCS) Food Rescue program in supermarkets.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into four series: Administrative records, Infographics and food collection data, Photographs, and Publicity. The Administrative records series has a subseries for minutes, which is closed for 20 years from date of creation. Received order has been maintained.
Student life; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative
- Administrative records, 2016 -- 2019; MS264.001; 5 Digital Object(s); 1.5 Megabytes
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  Arrangement
  Received order has been maintained.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the administrative records of the Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative, including meeting minutes, the group constitution, and logo.
  - Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative Constitution, 2019-01-31; MS264.001.00001; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 865 Kilobytes
    Open for research.
  - TFRC logo, circa 2016; MS264.001.00002; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 262 Kilobytes
  - Minutes, 2018 -- 2019; MS264.001.001; 3 Digital Object(s); 458 Kilobytes
    Minutes from Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative meetings.
    University records are closed for 20 years from the date of creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
    - TFRC Minutes, 2018-09-14; MS264.001.001.00001; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 136 Kilobytes
      20 years from date of creation.
    - TFRC Minutes, 2019-02-01; MS264.001.001.00002; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 160 Kilobytes
    - TFRC Minutes, 2019-04-12; MS264.001.001.00003; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 162 Kilobytes
- Infographics and food collection data, 2016 -- 2019; MS264.002; 7 Digital Object(s); 3.1 Megabytes
  Infographics with statistics from each semester and statistical data from each fiscal year.
  This series is open for research.
  - Food For Free Donations Data, 2017 -- 2019; MS264.002.00001; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Kilobytes
  - TFRC Spring 2018 summary Family Meals, 2016; MS264.002.00002; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 467 Kilobytes
  - TFRC Spring 2017 summary Family Meals, MS264.002.00003; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 880 Kilobytes
  - TFRC Fall 2017 summary Family Meals, MS264.002.00004; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 511 Kilobytes
  - TFRC Spring 2019 summary Family Meals, MS264.002.00005; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 464 Kilobytes
  - TFRC Fall 2018 summary Family Meals, MS264.002.00006; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 465 Kilobytes
  - TFRC Fall 2016 summary Family Meals, MS264.002.00007; Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative; 1 Digital Object(s); 384 Kilobytes
- Photographs, 2018; MS264.003; 11 Digital Object(s); 16.26 Megabytes
  Photographs of Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative volunteers in action and prepared meals.
  - Chicken and Rice meals, 2018; MS264.003.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.15 Megabytes
  - Meals, circa 2018; MS264.003.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.36 Megabytes
  - Four meals, 2018; MS264.003.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.95 Megabytes
  - Stack of meals, 2018; MS264.003.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.28 Megabytes
  - Meal trays being made, 2018; MS264.003.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.72 Megabytes
  - Emma and Isabel in Dewick, 2018; MS264.003.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.37 Megabytes
  - Dewick signage mid-Fall 2018, MS264.003.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.36 Megabytes
  - Volunteers and the Oliver Machine, 2018; MS264.003.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.66 Megabytes
  - Grace and Leslie in Carmichael, 2018; MS264.003.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.36 Megabytes
  - Art for Observer (credit to Madeline Lee), 2018; MS264.003.00010; Lee, Madeline; 1 Digital Object(s); 794 Kilobytes
  - Summer 2018 Whole Foods pickup -- sorting veggie boxes, MS264.003.00011; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.27 Megabytes
- Publicity, 2015 -- 2018; MS264.004; 7 Digital Object(s); 1.2 Megabytes
  PDFs of articles from the Tufts Daily and The Observer about the Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative.
  - Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative coordinates dining center food donation, 2016-09-20; MS264.004.00001; Tufts Daily; 1 Digital Object(s); 45 Kilobytes
  - Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative hosts Ethics of Eating event, 2017-10-26; MS264.004.00002; Tufts Daily; 1 Digital Object(s); 42 Kilobytes
  - Tufts Food Rescue Collaborative hosts Ethics of Eating event, 2017-10-26; MS264.004.00003; Tufts Daily; 1 Digital Object(s); 42 Kilobytes
  - Waste Less Dinner promotes sustainable eating on campus, 2018-11-14; MS264.004.00004; Tufts Daily; 1 Digital Object(s); 57 Kilobytes
  - Tufts Dining to begin pilot food donation program after ExCollege class petition, 2015-12-10; MS264.004.00005; Tufts Daily; 1 Digital Object(s); 42 Kilobytes
  - Left Over, 2016-04-25; MS264.004.00006; Observer; 1 Digital Object(s); 632 Kilobytes
  - The Food We Waste, 2018-10-29; MS264.004.00007; Observer; 1 Digital Object(s); 336 Kilobytes